Ridho Saifulhaq

+62 812-2707-7018 | saifulhaqridho28@gmail.com | Portfolio | Purworejo, Central Java

PROFILE

A Bachelor's graduate of Cartography and Remote Sensing at Gadjah Mada University with a strong passion for environmental and social studies, with a particular interest in environmental conservation, wildlife protection, and urban dynamics such as population growth, transportation, and migration. Experience in spatial analysis, geoprocessing, mapping, and geospatial technologies. Has proficiency in GIS software, excellent problem-solving skills, and advanced computer mapping skills. Highly passionate about solving real-world challenges in the geospatial field.

EDUCATION

Gadjah Mada University

Bachelor's Degree in Cartography & Remote Sensing (GPA 3.55 / 4.00)

2019 - 2023

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

PT Pangrancana Spasialindo Pratama

Geographic Information Systems (GIS) Technician

June 2024 - October 2024

- Created base maps and spatial structure maps for RDTR (Detailed Spatial Plan).
- Conducted spatial analysis, geo-processing, and database queries to support urban planning initiatives.
- Maintained accurate and up-to-date geospatial database to create maps, reports, dashboards, and other visual representations, generating insightful information to support the decision-making process.
- Recorded and managed all documentation for geospatial data and methodologies.
- Collaborated with teams and stakeholders to obtain data sources and gather feedback for urban planning.
- Established long-term partnerships and effective communication with external teams & relevant stakeholders.
- Provided assistance in meetings, research, administration, operations, and other data support.

Quadrant (POI Data-as-a-Service)

POI Verifier (Freelance)

November 2023 - May 2024

- Collected and verified POI (Point of Interest) data from field surveys, ensuring accurate and up-to-date datasets for supporting client's use cases and business requirements.
- Conducted comparison of collected POI (Point of Interest) and field data to ensure data quality and integrity.
- Provided comprehensive and actionable geospatial information on landmarks, key features, areas, and others.

ORGANIZATIONAL EXPERIENCES

Cartographic Laboratory, Gadjah Mada University

Laboratory Assistant – Digital Cartography

2022

- Delivered learning materials for Digital Cartography course, including animated maps, 3D maps, web maps, etc.
- Provided assignments and tests to assess students' level of understanding of each practicum session.
- Monitored students' learning progress throughout the semester and provided constructive feedback.

Geographic Information Science Laboratory, Gadjah Mada University

Laboratory Assistant – Spatial Programming

2022

- Conducted practicum classes for the Spatial Programming course, including demonstrating how to use geospatial programming applications (Visual Basic) and how to develop Web-GIS.
- Prepared learning materials (presentation slides, quizzes, tests, etc.) based on the applicable curriculum.
- Carried out the evaluation of students' level of understanding and learning progress throughout the semester.

Laboratory Assistant – Algorithm and Programming

2021

- Provided learning and practicum sessions for the Algorithm and Programming courses.
- Delivered programming concepts, including fundamental programming in Visual Basic and web development.
- Monitored and evaluated students' learning progress, ensuring the achievement of main learning objectives.

SKM Bulaksumur, Gadjah Mada University

Article Writer & Editor

2019 – 2021

- Researched trending and industry-related topics to develop ideas for news articles.
- Wrote article manuscripts, ensuring alignment with the organization's journalism standards.
- Performed editing and proofreading on news articles before publication to ensure the quality of the content.

PUBLICATION

Reconstructing Land Use Information for Parts of Klaten Regency and Surrounding Areas Using the Cellular Automata-Markov Chain Method (Author) – October, 2023 (Not Yet Published)

Analysis of Land Capability and Suitability for Middle-Class Housing Locations Based on Physical Aspects and Accessibility Using a Geographic Information System with Remote Sensing in Temon and Wates Districts, Kulonprogo Regency (Co-Author) – June, 2022 (Not Yet Published)

GIS for Geomorphological Analysis: Facies of Merapi Volcano and Morphometry of Gendol River (Co-Author) – December, 2021 (https://doi.org/10.1117/12.2619501)

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

Skill : Research, Geospatial Data Processing, Database Management, Data Visualization, Data Analysis,

Geo-Mapping, Surveying, Project Management, News & Article Writing, Reporting, Administration

Software : Microsoft Office (Word, Excel), SQL, ArcGIS, QGIS, AutoCAD, Google Earth Engine, Inkscape, Envi,

Idrisi, Agisoft PhotoScan, Visual Basic, Adobe After Effect, Wondershare Filmora

Language : Bahasa Indonesia (Native), English (Professional Working Proficiency)